Guide to the Josephine Herbst Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Josephine Herbst papers
1799-1969
1901-1969
YCAL MSS 474
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
52.87
(134 boxes)
The Josephine Herbst Papers document the work of novelist and journalist Josephine Herbst. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, notebooks, research files, printed material, personal and family papers, photographs, artwork, and personal effects spanning the years 1799 to 1969, with the bulk of the material dating from 1901 to 1969.
Herbst, Josephine, 1892-1969
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Josephine Herbst on the PL480 Fund, George B. Alvord Fund, Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, Hall Park McCullough Fund, William A. Taylor Memorial Fund, 1968 and on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 1985. Gift of Elinor Langer, 1989-1993.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Access to original sound recording is restricted pending reformatting. Consult the Beinecke Library Access Services department for reformatting requests.
Box 134 (reel-to-reel sound recording): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm service copies are available for film numbers 891, 973, 1151, 1171, 1722, 2480, 2589, and 3396.
Associated Materials
Associated material includes the Elinor Langer Collection of Josephine Herbst (YCAL MSS 475).
Other material by or relating to Josephine Herbst (various call numbers) can be found by searching the Uncataloged Acquisitions Database and Orbis (Yale's Online Catalog).
Josephine Herbst
Josephine Herbst (1892-1969) was an American writer and journalist. She was considered to be a radical writer, with communist leanings. Herbst's published works include Nothing is Sacred (1928); Money for Love (1929); the Trexler trilogy: Pity is Not Enough (1933), The Executioner Waits (1934), and Rope of Gold (1939); Satan's Sergeants (1941), Somewhere the Tempest Fell (1947), and New Green World (1954). Herbst was born in Sioux City, Iowa, on March 5, 1897 and died of cancer in New York City on January 28, 1969.
Scope and Contents
The Josephine Herbst Papers document the work of novelist and journalist Josephine Herbst. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, notebooks, research files, printed material, personal and family papers, photographs, artwork, and personal effects spanning the years 1799 to 1969, with the bulk of the material dating from 1901 to 1969.
The bulk of the collection consists of Herbst's correspondence and drafts of writings. Correspondence includes letters from friends, colleagues, and family members regarding her personal and professional life. Among the correspondence is third party correspondence, including correspondence between various members of her extended family. Writings include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, printed versions, notes, and notebooks of her writings, including novels, a play, reviews, magazine articles, short stories, essays, and her unfinished memoir, tentatively titled "A Year of Disgrace." Other papers include Frey and Herbst family correspondence and papers, writings of others, research material, early school material, photographs, financial and medical papers, artwork, personal effects, an unidentified sound recording, and printed material.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Correspondence, 1845-1969. II. Writings, 1901-1969. III. Other Papers, 1866-1969. IV. Frey and Herbst Family Papers, 1799-1913.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Photographs; Sound recordings; Herbst, Josephine, 1892-1969
- Correspondence, 1845-1969, undated; Series I; 13.44; (32 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseries: Correspondence with Josephine Herbst and Third Party Correspondence.
  - Correspondence with Josephine Herbst
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A small amount of unidentified correspondence, postcards, and correspondence regarding various subjects is filed at the end of the subseries.
    - "A" General, 1937-1968 (Box 1)
    - Allan, Ruth, 1946-1966 (Box 1)
    - Ames, Elizabeth, 1932-1958 (Box 1)
    - Amlie, Millie, 1941-1943 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Maxwell, 1920-1941 (Box 1)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1933-1935 (Box 1)
    - Asch, Nathan, 1937-1946 (Box 1)
    - Atlantic Monthly Press, 1958-1962 (Box 1)
    - "B" General, 1939-1968 (Box 2)
    - Baker, Carlos, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1958-1965 (Box 2)
    - Bernhard, Andrew, 1922-1961, undated; 4 (Box 2)
    - Bernhard, Anna, undated (Box 2)
    - Barry, Griffith, 1944, undated (Box 2)
    - Bartram, John, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Bein, Mary, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
    - Berkman, Sylvia, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Bland, Alden, 1946, undated (Box 2)
    - Boyden, Polly, 1941-1951 (Box 2)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1926-1956 (Box 3)
    - Briskin, Irene, 1958-1968, undated (Box 3)
    - Brown, Fred, 1964-1965, undated (Box 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes "Aragon" typescript carbon
    - Burnshaw, Stanley, 1959-1968, undated; 2 (Box 3)
    - Butler, Virginia, 1944 (Box 3)
    - Byrdy, Harold, 1956-1966, undated (Box 3)
    - "C" General, 1929-1968, undated (Box 3)
    - Cahill, Dorothy and Holger, 1930-1967, undated (Box 3)
    - "California Universities", 1933-1954 (Box 3)
    - Callaghan, Morley, 1929-1965, undated (Box 3)
    - Centaur Book Shop, 1931-1932, undated (Box 3)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1931-1965; 2 (Box 3)
    - Cheever, John, 1942-1957, undated; 2 (Box 4)
    - Clark, Eleanor, 1936-1954 (Box 4)
    - Cloe, Fleta, 1944-1947, undated (Box 4)
    - Cohen, Arthur A, 1956 (Box 4)
    - Cohn, Marvin, 1955-1965, undated (Box 4)
    - Commentary, 1959-1964 (Box 4)
    - "Coward - McCann", 1928-1966, undated (Box 4)
    - "Crawford", 1932-1957 (Box 4)
    - Curley, Dan, 1957-1965 (Box 4)
    - "D" General, 1932-1958, undated (Box 4)
    - Dahlberg, Edward, 1950-1968; 3 (Box 4)
    - Daniels, Neal and Mary, 1966-1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Davis, Betty, 1935-1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Davis, Mr. and Mrs. Hampton, 1947-1966, undated (Box 5)
    - Davis, Ken and Flo, 1958-1959, undated (Box 5)
    - Deutsch, Babette, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - di Giovanni, Norman Thomas, 1959-1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Dos Passos, John, 1929-1949, undated (Box 5)
    - Durant, Kenneth, 1949-1951 (Box 5)
    - "E" General, 1931-1966 (Box 5)
    - Eastman, Max, 1923-1924, undated (Box 5)
    - Eppley, Alice, 1925 (Box 5)
    - Everett, Edith, 1937-1951, undated (Box 5)
    - "F" General, 1937-1962 (Box 5)
    - Fadiman, Clifton, 1928-1932 (Box 5)
    - Farrar, Straus, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
    - Farrell, James T., 1934-1957, undated (Box 5)
    - Fenn, Charles, 1947-1949 (Box 5)
    - Freeman, Joe, 1924-1963, undated; 7 (Box 6)
      Includes speech at Smith College
    - Friede, Donald S., 1945-1947 (Box 7)
    - Friedman, Ray, 1964-1965 (Box 7)
    - Fry, Daniel J., 1927-1930 (Box 7)
    - Fuchs, Daniel, 1937, undated (Box 7)
    - "G" General, 1922-1968, undated (Box 7)
    - Garrigue, Jean, 1950-1968, undated; 2 (Box 7)
    - Garrigue, Jean, 1950-1968, undated; 11 (Box 8)
    - Gehman, Richard B, 1920-1966 (Box 9)
    - Georgia Review, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Gordon, Caroline, 1929-1935, undated (Box 9)
    - Greenwood, Marion, 1932-1945, undated; 5 (Box 9)
    - Griffin, Howard, 1958-1959, undated (Box 9)
    - Guggenheim, 1935-1957 (Box 9)
    - "H" General, 1929-1967, undated (Box 9)
    - Hall, Ben, 1954, undated (Box 9)
    - Halse, Laura M, 1949, undated (Box 9)
    - Hamburger, Philip and Edith, 1944-1966 (Box 9)
    - Hansen, Alice and John, 1926-1941 (Box 10)
    - Hansen, Alice, 1920-1957; 2 (Box 10)
    - Hansen, Betty, 1936 (Box 10)
    - Hansen, Pauline, 1950-1951, undated (Box 10)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company and Inc., 1933-1956 (Box 10)
    - Hastings House Publishers, Inc., 1950-1965; 2 (Box 10)
    - Hawkes, John, 1960-1963 (Box 10)
    - Hellmann, Lilian, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1928-1935 (Box 10)
    - Hemley, Cecil & Elaine, 1952-1967 (Box 10)
    - Herbst family letters, 1918-1925 (Box 10)
    - Herbst, Helen, 1909-1920, undated; 3 (Box 11)
    - Herbst, Mary and William Benton, 1921-1925; 5 (Box 11)
    - Herbst, Mary and William Benton, 1919-1923; 5 (Box 12)
    - Herbst, Mary and William Benton, 1922-1925; 3 (Box 13)
    - Herbst, William Benton, 1923-1929; 3 (Box 13)
    - Herrmann, John, 1924 (Box 13)
    - Herrmann, John, 1925-1938; 7 (Box 14)
    - Herrmann, John, 1935-1959, undated; 7 (Box 15)
    - Herrmann, Richard, undated (Box 15)
    - Herschberger, Ruth, 1958, undated (Box 15)
    - Hicks, Granville, 1934-1937 (Box 15)
    - Hildebrandt, Laura, 1949-1958 (Box 15)
    - Houghton-Mifflin, 1959 (Box 15)
    - "I" General, 1931-1958, undated (Box 15)
    - Imbs, Bravis and Valeska, 1930-1949 (Box 15)
    - Iowa State University, 1946-1966 (Box 15)
    - "J" General, 1938-1964 (Box 15)
    - "K" General, 1932-1964, undated (Box 16)
    - Katz, Leslie, 1957-1968, undated (Box 16)
    - Kazin, Alfred, 1950-1968, undated; 3 (Box 16)
    - Kirstein, Elinor, 1951, undated (Box 16)
    - Kubly, Herbert, 1959, undated (Box 16)
    - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1927, undated (Box 16)
    - Kenyon Review, 1962-1968 (Box 16)
    - Kramer, Hilton, 1957-1968 (Box 16)
    - "L" General, 1926-1963 (Box 16)
    - Laning, Claire, 1941-1965, undated; 8 (Box 17)
    - Laning, Helen and Lucile, 1959; 2 (Box 17)
    - Lawrence, Sam, 1962, undated; 2 (Box 17)
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1931-1953 (Box 18)
    - Lloyd, Mary, 1949-1967 (Box 18)
    - "M" General, 1929-1966, undated (Box 18)
    - MacDowell Colony, 1957-1960 (Box 18)
    - Madden, David, 1966-1968 (Box 18)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1928-1955, undated; 2 (Box 18)
    - McKay, Claude, 1924 (Box 18)
    - "M" General, 1932-1965, undated (Box 19)
    - Marberry, Virginia, 1967-1968, undated (Box 19)
    - Mayhall, Jane, 1958-1968; 2 (Box 19)
    - Mencken, H.L., 1923-1949 (Box 19)
    - Miller, Charles, 1966-1968; 2 (Box 19)
    - Mitchell, Burroughs, 1958 (Box 19)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1954 (Box 19)
    - "N" General, 1952-1968 (Box 19)
    - The Nation, 1937-1966 (Box 19)
    - National Book Award, 1968 (Box 19)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1950-1967 (Box 19)
    - Neiman, Gilbert, 1946-1947 (Box 19)
    - New Directions, 1963-1966 (Box 19)
    - New Masses, 1927-1954, undated (Box 19)
    - New Republic, 1931-1966, undated (Box 20)
    - New Yorker, 1943-1947, undated (Box 20)
    - Newberry Library, 1957-1967 (Box 20)
    - North, Helen, 1935-1955, undated (Box 20)
    - "O" General, 1931-1968, undated (Box 20)
    - O'Conner, Jessie Lloyd, 1947-1968 (Box 20)
    - Orget, Irene, 1954-1956, undated (Box 20)
    - "P" General, 1928-1968, undated (Box 20)
    - Perkins, Max, 1930-1946 (Box 20)
    - Persons, Simmons, 1955-1956 (Box 20)
    - Phillips, William, 1935-1936, undated; 2 (Box 20)
    - Phillips, William "General Lee Goes Marching On", undated (Box 20)
    - Pickering, Martha, 1968-1969 (Box 20)
    - Pitts, Rebecca, 1944-1968; 2 (Box 21)
    - Pollet, Elizabeth, 1955-1966, undated; 2 (Box 21)
    - Porter, Katherine (duplicate xerox copies), 1927-1962; 4 (Box 21)
    - Pratt, Dorothy and Richard, 1962-1963 (Box 21)
    - Prentice-Hall, 1964-1965, undated (Box 21)
    - Quilhot, 1928 (Box 22)
    - "R" General, 1927-1968, undated (Box 22)
    - Randolph, Edna, undated (Box 22)
    - Regler, Gustav, 1947-1957, undated (Box 22)
    - Resist, 1967 (Box 22)
    - Ritchie, Paul, 1963-1967 (Box 22)
    - Reuben, William A., 1968 (Box 22)
    - Robinson, J.A., 1942-1947; 2 (Box 22)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1965-1967 (Box 22)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1927-1928 (Box 22)
    - Rogovin, 1964-1966 (Box 22)
    - Roth, Philip, 1967-1968 (Box 22)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1941-1943, undated (Box 22)
    - Russell-Volkening Inc., 1948-1968 (Box 22)
    - "S" General, 1926-1967, undated (Box 23)
    - Schiddel, Edmund, 1953-1959 (Box 23)
    - Schneider, Isadore, 1931, undated (Box 23)
    - Seaver, Edwin, 1965 (Box 23)
    - Sebree, Charles, 1951, undated (Box 23)
    - Seldes, Helen and George, 1937-1940, undated (Box 23)
    - Sennett, Maurice R., 1943-1952, undated (Box 23)
    - Seymour Lawrence, Inc., 1965-1967 (Box 23)
    - Snodgress, W.D., 1959 (Box 23)
    - Stern, Max, 1920-1922 (Box 23)
    - Stevenson, Philip, 1932-1962, undated (Box 23)
    - Southern Illinois University, 1965 (Box 23)
    - "T" General, 1939-1962, undated (Box 23)
    - Taggard, Genevieve, 1920-1942, undated; 2 (Box 23)
      Includes letters to Bob Wolf
    - Tate, Allen, 1962 (Box 23)
    - Tomorrow, 1943-1951 (Box 23)
    - Turnbull, Andrew, 1962 (Box 23)
    - "U" General, 1934-1956, undated (Box 23)
    - "V" General, 1926-1967, undated (Box 24)
    - Van Arkel, Gerhard P., 1954-1955, undated (Box 24)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1944-1954 (Box 24)
    - Vorse, Mary, 1939-1949, undated (Box 24)
    - "W" General, 1930-1968, undated (Box 24)
    - Wagner Literary Magazine, 1961-1962 (Box 24)
    - Waldman, Arthur M., 1948-1951 (Box 24)
    - Walkin, F., 1920-1921 (Box 24)
    - Walsh, J.F., 1920, undated (Box 24)
    - Walter, Eugene, 1952-1956, undated (Box 24)
    - Watson, William B., 1967 (Box 24)
    - Welch, Norval, 1954-1955 (Box 24)
    - Wells, Ben, 1958-1966 (Box 24)
    - Wells, Frances, 1913-1956, undated; 7 (Box 25)
    - Wells, Frances, 1913-1956, undated; 9 (Box 26)
    - West, Nathanael, 1933-1968 (Box 27)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1962-1968 (Box 27)
    - Wertz, Mr. and Mrs., 1926-1928 (Box 27)
    - Who's Who, 1933-1965, undated (Box 27)
    - Williams, Lucita, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
    - Williams, A. Rhys, 1909-1968, undated; 3 (Box 27)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1933-1961; 2 (Box 27)
    - Williams, Oscar, undated (Box 27)
    - Wolf, Robert L., 1920-1925; 2 (Box 27)
    - Woolf, Samuel, 1943 (Box 27)
    - Wolfson, Victor, 1941, undated (Box 27)
    - Wright, Clifford and Elsa, 1954-1963 (Box 27)
    - "Y" General, 1933-1967, undated (Box 27)
    - "Z" General, 1958-1962, undated (Box 27)
    - Zur Muhlen, Hermynia, 1929-1931 (Box 27)
    - ___, Erma, 1929 (Box 28)
    - ___, Laurie, undated (Box 28)
    - ___, Miriam, 1920 (Box 28)
    - Unidentified and unsorted correspondence, 1909-1967, undated; 3 (Box 28)
    - Postcards A-Z, 1923-1968, undated; 3 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence regarding
      - Addresses, undated (Box 29)
      - Archive. Correspondence with Yale, Texas, et. al. concerning disposition of Herbst papers, 1968 (Box 29)
      - International Literature, 1935-1939 (Box 29)
      - Newberry Library Conference on American Studies, 1957 (Box 29)
      - Political correspondence, 1932-1961 (Box 29)
      - Taxes, Medicare, etc., 1944-1968 (Box 29)
      - Travel, 1965, undated (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous items, 1931-1954, undated (Box 29)
      - "Magazine assignments", 1931-1952, undated (Box 29)
    - Third Party Correspondence
      This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
      Additional Herbst family correspondence is in Series IV. Frey and Herbst Family Papers.
      - Asch, Nathan to John Herrmann, 1924-1932, undated (Box 30)
      - Bernhard, Andrew to Mary Herbst, 1918 (Box 30)
      - Bolig family to William Benton Herbst, 1922-1928 (Box 30)
      - Collins, Emily R. to Ruth Allen Stahl, 1923-1928 (Box 30)
      - Eppley, Alice (Fry) to her Mary Herbst, 1894-1925, undated (Box 30)
      - Fry, Daniel to Helen Herbst and Mary Herbst, 1890-1921 (Box 30)
      - Fry, Daniel J. to his Mary Herbst, 1883-1921 (Box 30)
      - Fry Family, 1845-1921 (Box 30)
      - Fry, Marcus to his sister Mary Herbst, 1869-1912 (Box 30)
      - Fry, Marcus correspondence with W. B. Herbst, 1925-1926 (Box 30)
      - Gold, Michael, undated (Box 31)
      - Goodwin, Norbert to John Hermann, 1931-1936, undated (Box 31)
      - Hansen, Alice (Herbst) to William Benton Herbst, 1929 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Mr. and Mrs. James H. and cards to William Benton Herbst, 1926-1928 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Helen (Bernard) to Mary Herbst, 1913-1920 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Helen to William Benton Herbst, 1913 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Helen to Mary Herbst, 1908-1919 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Helen to Frances Wells, 1920 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Mary to Andrew Bernhard, 1922 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Mary Frey to Josephine Herbst, 1912-1922 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, William Benton to Mary Fry Herbst, 1883-1884 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Mary to William Benton Herbst, 1918-1923 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Mary to Marcus Fry, 1886-1911; 2 (Box 31)
      - Herbst, Mary to William Benton Herbst, 1886-1918 (Box 32)
      - Herbst, Mary to Helen Herbst, 1914-1918; 2 (Box 32)
      - Herbst, Mary to J. Herbst, 1920-1924 (Box 32)
      - Herbst, Mary to J. Herbst, 1915-1922 (Box 32)
      - Walsh, Jane Fry, 1915-1965 (Box 32)
      - Herbst, Mary to Frances Wells, 1918 (Box 32)
      - Herbst, Mildred G. to William Benton Herbst, 1925-1926 (Box 32)
      - Herbst, William Benton to Mary Herbst, 1891-1918 (Box 32)
      - Letters to John Herrmann, 1926-1932 (Box 32)
      - Herrmann, John to "Mother", 1916 (Box 32)
      - Hicks, Granville to Marion Greenwood, 1932 (Box 32)
      - Houck, Catherine and Powell card to William Benton Herbst, 1928 (Box 32)
      - Hunt, Leigh to John Herrmann, 1925 (Box 32)
      - Lieber, Maxim to John Herrmann, 1931-1936 (Box 32)
      - Meaces, Bertha M. to William Benton Herbst, 1925 (Box 32)
      - Miller, Emma Herbs to William Benton Herbst, 1925-1928 (Box 32)
      - Park, Mr. and Mrs. W. J. announcement to William Benton and Mary Herbst, 1928 (Box 32)
      - Rosenfeld, Paul to John Herrmann, 1926-1927, undated (Box 32)
      - Sage, Robert to John Herrmann, 1924-1931, undated (Box 32)
      - Williams, Mr. and Mrs. W. Raymond cards to William Benton Herbst, 1926-1927 (Box 32)
      - Worthington, Marjorie to Clair Laning, 1947 (Box 32)
- Writings, 1901-1969, undated; Series II; 21.74; (61 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries: Writings by Herbst and Writings by Others.
  Writings by Herbst include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, corrected and uncorrected, drafts and printed versions, and notes and notebooks of her writings, including novels, a play, reviews, magazine articles, short stories, essays, and her unfinished memoir, tentatively titled "A Year of Disgrace."
  Writings by Others includes drafts and printed versions of writings collected by Herbst.
  - Writings by Herbst
    Most titles are arranged alphabetically. Some titles are grouped together out of alphabetical order.
    - Early Writings (childhood, high school and college notebooks, journals, essays), 1901-1913, undated; 9 (Box 33)
    - Following the Circle, 1925; 4 (Box 34)
    - "Hour of Counterfeit Bliss" and "The Ground We Tread and Outlines", undated; 15 (Box 35)
    - Hunter of Doves, 1952; 7 (Box 36)
      Also titled "Hunter in the Sky"
    - New Green World, undated; 23 (Box 38)
    - New Green World, undated; 17 (Box 39)
    - Nothing is Sacred, undated; 7 (Box 37)
    - Pity is Not Enough, 39 (Box 40)
    - Pity is Not Enough (Box 41)
    - Rope of Gold, 8 (Box 42)
    - Satan's Sergeants, 3 (Box 43)
    - The Watcher with the Horn, 8 (Box 44)
    - "Year of Russian Revolution", 25 (Box 45)
      Ghostwritten by Herbst for Albert Rhys Williams
    - "A Year of Disgrace" or "Memoirs", 2 (Box 46)
    - "A Year of Disgrace" or "Memoirs", 26 (Box 47)
    - "A Year of Disgrace" or "Memoirs", 13 (Box 48)
    - "A Year of Disgrace" or "Memoirs", 4 (Box 49)
    - "A Year of Disgrace" or "Memoirs", 4 (Box 50)
    - "A Year of Disgrace" or "Memoirs", 4 (Box 51)
    - Reviews: Money for Love, The Executioner Waits, Somewhere the Tempest Fell, 3 (Box 52)
    - Unfinished Works: "New York Scene," "If," and "The Attic of the Soul", 10 (Box 53)
    - 1. "Bright Signal" 2. "Nathaniel West", 7 (Box 54)
    - Short Stories, 17 (Box 55)
    - 1. Play (untitled, unfinished) 2. "Ventures in Verse" 3. "Outside Time" (Gustav Regler story), 9 (Box 56)
    - 1. "The Lady and the Unicorn" 2. Piece on Dahlberg 3. Article on Van Gogh Exhibit, 10 (Box 57)
    - 1. Article on Yugoslavia 2. Partial draft of play regarding Hitler; notes on Germany in 30s and 40s, 3 (Box 58)
    - 1. "Feet in the Grassroots" 2. Notes on the farm situation (U.S.) 1934-1935, 29 (Box 59)
    - Writings, notes, and printed material on
      - Cuba, 15 (Box 60)
      - Cuba, 5 (Box 133)
      - South America, 24 (Box 61)
      - Spain, 12 (Box 62)
    - Printed versions of writings by Herbst, 6 (Box 63)
    - Printed versions of writings by Herbst, 8 (Box 64)
    - Printed versions of writings by Herbst, 16 (Box 65)
    - Notes, 1858-1965, undated
      Includes writings by family members. This material needs to be further sorted.
      - Notes, 40 (Box 66)
      - Notes, 21 (Box 67)
      - Notes, 17 (Box 68)
      - Notes, 5 (Box 69)
      - Notes, 9 (Box 70)
      - Notes, 8 (Box 71)
      - Notes, 7 (Box 72)
      - Notes, 4 (Box 73)
    - Notebooks
      - Notebooks, 6 (Box 74)
      - Notebooks, 7 (Box 75)
      - Notebooks, 8 (Box 76)
      - Notebooks, 5 (Box 77)
      - Notebooks, 5 (Box 78)
    - Writings by others
      - Writings drafts of others, 5 (Box 79)
      - Printed versions of writings of others
        Arranged alphabetically by publication and author name
        - A-G, 11 (Box 80)
        - H-M, 13 (Box 81)
        - N-O, 10 (Box 82)
        - New Statesman, 1959-1964; 7 (Box 83)
        - P-Z, 11 (Box 84)
        - Unsorted, 8 (Box 85)
      - Pamphlets: artistic, literary, miscellaneous, 6 (Box 86)
      - Pamphlets: political, miscellaneous, 18 (Box 87)
      - Pamphlets: political, miscellaneous, 3 (Box 88)
      - Assorted newspaper clippings, 17 (Box 89)
      - Assorted newspaper clippings, 5 (Box 90)
      - Galleys, 8 (Box 91)
      - Galleys, 9 (Box 92)
- Other Papers, 1866-1969, undated; Series III; 12.62; (28 boxes)
  Organized into four subseries: Early School Material, Photographs, Personal Papers, and Other Papers.
  - Early School Material
    - Sioux City school yearbooks, 1906-1911; 6 (Box 93)
    - Sioux City school yearbooks, 1912-1913; 3 (Box 94)
    - "The Girl Graduate: Her Own Book" scrapbook, Josephine Herbst, 1910 (Box 95)
    - Josephine and Helen Herbst's composition books, circa 1905-1910; 5 (Box 96)
  - Photographs
    Not arranged in any particular order.
    - Photograph album, 1866 (Box 97)
      Inscribed by Joseph Frey
    - Photograph album. "Photo-remembrances from the All-Ukranian Society of Friends of the Soviet Photography Cinematography and of the Ukranian Film of the capital of the Soviet Union.", 1930 November (Box 98)
    - Photographs, 5 (Box 99)
    - Photographs, 3 (Box 100)
    - Photographs (Box 101)
  - Personal Papers
    - Financial (Box 102)
      - Cancelled checks, 1930-1965
      - Contracts, Royalties, Etc., 1921-1945
      - Financial papers, 1957-1967
      - Legal, Financial Misc., 1929-1968
      - Taxes, Medicare, etc., 1931-1968; 2
    - Medical (Box 103)
      - Hospital and medical bills and medical notes, 1966
      - Medical, 1966-1968
    - War documents and passport, 1922-1943, undated; 12 (Box 104)
    - Items removed from safety deposit box, 1877-1950; 11 (Box 105)
    - Personal effects, undated (Box 106)
      Personal effects include boxes, statue, name stamp, doll, and small framed art objects
    - Personal effects, undated (Box 107)
  - Other Papers
    - Unidentified reel-to-reel sound recording, undated
    - Artwork, 9 (Box 109)
      Includes work and material by Helen Herbst
    - Artwork, 7 (Box 110)
    - Artwork (Box 111)
    - Index cards for books in Herbst's personal library, undated (Box 112)